Partial Guide to the Memorial Library of Music Collection
Department of Special Collections
- Zwei Gesänge für eine Altstimme mit Bratsche und Pianoforte von Johannes Brahms. / BRAHMS, JOHANNES (1833-1897), MLM 145
  Op. 91 ... Berlin, N. Simrock, 1884. P1. no. 8474-8476. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. Inscription reads: ""An Frl. Marie Ruckert In Verehrung des honen Dichters gedenkend. J. Brahms"" The songs are ""Gestillte Sehnsucht"" and ""Geistliches Wiegenlied.""
- An engraved portrait. / BRAHMS, JOHANNES (1833-1897), MLM 145A
  Portrait of the composer (Weger, Leipzig).
- Andante ben moderato e tranquillo. / BRIDGE, FRANK (1879-1941), MLM 146
  Original manuscript signed. 2 leaves (title-page as above, 1 page) 38 x 28 cm. The gift of Mrs. Bridge.
- Processional [by] Frank Bridge. / BRIDGE, FRANK (1879-1941), MLM 147
  London, J. Curwen & Sons, 1940. Pl. no. 99094. Inscribed to Archibald Martin Henderson by the composer. Page proofs.
- [A note signed] to Frank Bridge / BRIDGE, FRANK (1879-1941), MLM 147A
  from Walford Davis
- A ceremony of carols [by] Benjamin Britten. / BRITTEN, BENJAMIN (1913-), MLM 148
  Op. 28. [New York] Boosey & Hawkes, c1943. P1. no. H. 15576. Caption-title. First edition. Signed by the composer. Harp or piano and vocal score.
- Peter Grimes / BRITTEN, BENJAMIN (1913-), MLM 149
  An opera in three acts and a prologue derived from the poem by George Crabbe. Words by Montagu Slater. Music by Benjamin Britten. Op. 33. Vocal score by Erwin Stein. London, New York, Boosey & Hawkes [c1945] P1. no. H. 15730. First edition. Signed by the composer.
- Gloriana, opera in 3 parts. Plomer, music by B. Britten, Op. 53." / BRITTEN, BENJAMIN (1913-), MLM 149A
- Heldenfeier, opus 89." / BRUCH, MAX (1838-1920), MLM 150
  Original manuscript signed. 1915. 8 leaves(16 pages) 27x331/2 cm. Score for organ and choir. Words by Margarete Bruch.
- Das Lied von der Glocke. / BRUCH, MAX (1838-1920), MLM 151
  Gedicht von Friedrich von Schiller für Chor, vier Solostimmen, Orchester und Orgel. Componirt von Max Bruch. Op. 45...Translated into English by Mrs. Natalia Macfarren. Berlin, N. Sirnrock, 1879. P1. no. 8088. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. Text in English and German.
- [Sketches, piano, C major, E major, A major]" / BRUCKNER, ANTON (1824-1896), MLM 152
  Original manuscript signed. 2 leaves (1 page) 33 x 251/2 cm. At upper right of p. 1: ""Zum no. 29."" In text: ""Frei 6-Diss. im Durchg., Variat., Hauptsatz a, Inversio b, a ad II, b ad II."" Seven variations on a seven-bar theme.
- L'amoureuse leçon. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 153
  Ballet en un acte d'après Catulle Mendès. Poème et musique de Alfred Bruneau. Partition piano et chant. Paris, Choudens, ca. 1913. P1. no. A. C. 14,384. First edition. inscribed to Albert Renard by the composer.
- Chansons d'enfance et de jeunesse. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 154
  Poèmes de Marceline Desbordes-Valmore. Musique de Alfred Bruneau. Paris, Heugel, 1928. P1. nos. 29845-29854. Proof sheets of first edition with composer's corrections throughout.
- Les chants de la vie. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 155
  Poèmes de Henry Bataille, Saint-Georges de Bouhélier et Fernand Gregh. Musique de Alfred Bruneau. Paris, Choudens, c1913. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. Piano and vocal score.
- La faute de l'Abbé Mouret. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 156
  Pièce en quatre actes avec musique tirèe du roman d'Emile Zola par Alfred Bruneau... Partition piano et choeur. Paris, Choudens, c1907. P1. no. A. C. 13,657. First edition. inscribed to M. Debuchy by the composer.
- Geneviève. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 157
  Scène lyrique. Poésie de Mr. Ed. Guinand. Musique de A. Bruneau.. .Paris, E. et A. Girod [1881] P1. no. E. & A. G. 5915. First edition. Inscribed to M. Lespette by the composer. Piano and vocal score. Presented for the first time at Paris, October 22,1881.
- Kérim. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 158
  Opéra en 3 actes. Poème de Paul Milliet & Henri Lavedan. Musique de Alfred Bruneau. Partition piano & chant réduite par l'auteur... Paris, Enoch Frères & Costallat [ca. 1887] P1. no. B.P. 4829. First edition. Inscribed to Emmanuel Chabrier by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, May, 1887.
- Les lieds de France de Catulle Mendès. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 159
  Mis en musique par Alfred Bruneau... Paris, Choudens [1891] P1. no. A. C. 8775. First edition. Inscribed to Emmanuel Chabrier by the composer.
- Naïs Micoulin. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 160
  Drame lyrique en deux actes tiré de la nouvelle d'Emile Zola. Poème et musique de Alfred Bruneau. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Choudens, c1907. P1. no. 13,658. First edition. Inscribed to Marthe Chenal by the composer. Presented for the first time at Monte Carlo, 1907.
- L'ouragan. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 161
  Drame Iyrique en quatre actes. Poème de Emile Zola. Musique de Alfred Bruneau. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Choudens, c1901. P1. no. A. C. 11,806. First edition. inscribed to Marthe Chenal by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, 1901.
- [Penthesilée] / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 162
  Original manuscript with the title "Penthesilée, poème symphonique avec chant." A fragment of the orchestral score. 1888. 1 leaf (1 page) 27 x 35 cm. Inscribed to Eugene Ysaÿe by the composer.
- Les quatre journées. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 163
  Conte lyrique en quatre actes et cinq tableaux d'après Emile Zola. Poème et musique de Alfred Bruneau. Partition chant et piano. Réduite par l'auteur. Paris, Choudens, c1916. P1. no. A. C. 14,309. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Dolorès de Silvera by the composer. Mlle. de Silvera sang the role of Marguerite in the first performance at the Théâtre National de l'Opéra-Comique, Paris, December 19, 1916.
- La rêve. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 164
  Drame lyrique en quatre actes et 8 tableaux d'après le roman d'Emile Zola. Poème de Louis Gallet. Musique de Alfred Bruneau. Partition chant et piano transcrite par l'auteur. Paris, Choudens Fils [ca. 1891] P1. no. A. C. 8428. Inscribed to M. Warot by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, June 8, 1891. La rêve was widely discussed because of its bold harmonic structure and original style. It introduced a novel note of realism and vigor into French opera. Wotquenne, 2644.
- Le roi Candaule. / BRUNEAU, LOUIS CHARLES BONAVENTURE ALFRED (1857-1934), MLM 165
  Comédie lyrique en quatre actes et cinq tableaux. Poème de Maurice Donnay .-.. Musique de Alfred Bruneau. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Choudens, c1920. P1. no. A. C. 15,024. First edition. Inscribed to Emile Archaimbaud by the composer. Archaimbaud was one of the two ""Chefs des Choeurs"" at the first performance at the Théâtre National de 1'Opéra-Comique, Paris, December 1, 1920. Inserted is an autograph letter signed. To Emile Archaimbaud. Paris, December 2, 1920. This refers to the first performance of Le roi Candaule and Archaimbaud's part in it.
- [Mazurka-fantaisie, opus 13]" / BULOW, HANS GUIDO, FREIHERR VON (1830-1894), MLM 166
  Transcription for orchestra by Franz Liszt. Original manuscript. Signed by Liszt. 1864. 8 leaves (15 pages) 24 x 331/2 cm. Inscribed to M. Krause by von Büllow.
- As I looked o'er yon castle wa'. / BURNS, ROBERT (1759-1796), MLM 167
  Original manuscript. Music and text. 1 leaf (1 page) 30 x 141/2 cm. With a note in Burns's handwriting at the head of the manuscript: ""These words are inserted only to shew how the tune goes-they cannot be publ'd.-but the first stanza of the song I have sent, will suit as well."" In full red levant case with manuscript of song by Burns, ""Wap & row.""
- Buy braw troggin. / BURNS, ROBERT (1759-1796), MLM 168
  An excellent new song. Tune... Buy brooms besoms. n. p., 1796 1 leaf (2 pages) 81/2 x 201/2 cm. Mounted in a volume made up of 16 blank leaves. Bookplates of W. Crabbe Angus and John A. Spoor. This election song is the fourth and last of a series written by Robert Burns in connection with the parliamentary contest for the stewardry of Kirkandbright in 1795-1796. It was written in 1796 when the dissolution of Parliament again threw Heron into the turmoil of election. The poet was confined to a sickbed, but could not refrain from penning these lines in support of the recently successful candidates whose second triumph he did not live to enjoy. This copy has additional letters added to the proper names in the handwriting of Robert Burns, which have a special and pathetic interest as having been filled in within a few weeks of his death. (Taken from note on flyleaf.)
- Wap & row, wap & row:" / BURNS, ROBERT (1759-1796), MLM 169
  Original manuscript. Words only.
- Indianische Fantasie für Kiavier mit Orchester [von] Ferruccio Busoni. / BUSONI, FERRUCCIO BENVENUTO (1866-1924), MLM 170
  Op. 44. Leipzig, Breitkopf & Härtel, c.1915 [caption title] P1. no. B 2346. First edition. This composition is based upon American Indian themes. Busoni visited America five times, 1891-1915.
- Les noces Corinthiennes. / BUSSER, HENRI PAUL (1872-), MLM 171
  Tragédie lyrique en trois actes et quatre tableaux dont un prologue. Poème de Anatole France... Musique de Henri Busser. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Choudens, c1922. P1. no. A. C. 14,976. First edition. Inscribed to Emile Archaimbaud by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, May 10, 1922. Inserted are two autograph letters signed. To Emile Archaimbaud, Paris, February 10, May 12, 1922. These relate to the production of Les noces Corinthiennes.
- Sinfonia per la festa di S. Antonio. / CAPOTORTI, LUIGI (1767-1867), MLM 172
  Original manuscript signed. 1836. 1 leaf (2 pages) 291/2 x 221/2 cm. According to the learned Neopolitan archivist and historian, Francesco Florio, manuscripts of Capotorti are extremely rare. He was born in Malfetta, near Naples, studied at the Conservatorio S. Onofrio, and was chiefly an opera composer. This is reflected in the overture for Saint Anthony's Day. Scored for one flute, two oboes, clarinets, bassoons, horns, trumpets, and strings, it displays less religious spirit and more operatic traits instead.
- Méha. / CAPOUL, JOSEPH VICTOR AMEDEE (1839-1924), MLM 173
  Chanson hongroise. Paroles et musique de Victor Capoul. Original manuscript signed. Piano and vocal score. 2 leaves (3 pages) 27 x 35 cm. Capoul, the famous French operatic tenor, appears here in an unfamiliar role as a composer. Capoul made his American debut at the Academy of Music, New York City, November 22, 1871, with Christine Nilsson in the first American performance of Mignon.
- La prison d'Edimbourg. / CARAFA DI COLOBRANO, MICHELE ENRICO (1787-1872), MLM 174
  Opéra comique en 3 actes. Paroles de MM. Scribe et Planard. Musique de Ml. Carafa. Partition réduite avec accompagnement de piano. Der Kerker von Edimburg. Romantische Oper in drei Aufzügen nach dem französischen der Scribe & Planard. Musik von Ml. Carafa, für die deutsche Bühne bearbeitet, von J. D. Anton, vollstaendiger Clavier-Auszug von Joseph Rummel... Mainz, B. Schott's Söhnen [1833] P1. no 3914. First edition. The text is based on Sir Walter Scott's Heart of Midlothian.
- Beatrice, cantata pel centenario di Dante di Napoleone Giotti." / CASAMORATA, LUIGI FERDINANDO (1807-1881), MLM 175
  Original manuscript signed. 1865. 46 leaves (91 pages) 30 x 23 cm. A finely written manuscript whose first page shows the appeal: ""Onorate 'l altissimo poeta."" Born in Würzburg, Germany, of Italian parentage, Casamorata spent most of his life in Florence.
- Concerto in la minore per violino ed orchestra: a - primo tempo; b - adagio; c - rondo-trascrizione per violino e pianoforte dell'autore. Alfredo Casella. (A. D. MCMXXVIII) / CASELLA, ALFREDO (1883 - ), MLM 176
  At end of score: ""Cominciato il 13/2 MCMXXVII a Roma-terminato il 2/7 MCMXXVIII a Boston, Mass."" Original manuscript signed. 25 leaves, 47 pages. This was performed for the first time by Joseph Szigeti and the Persymphans in Moscow, October 8, 1928. Casella's new tonal creed finds expression in this composition.
- [Serenata Andalusa] / CATALANI, ALFREDO (1854-1893), MLM 177
  Al celebre violinista Tivadar Nacheèz. Serenata Andalusa per violino e pianoforte d' Alfredo Catalani. Original manuscript signed. 1887. 7 leaves (title, 12 pages) 24 x 35cm. Catalani, well known for his operas Loreley and La Wally, has provided a very effective composition for the violin virtuoso. This is divided into four, melodically different, sections and contains 210 measures. There is a facsimile of the first page of the score in Abbiati's Storia della musica, IV, p. 232.
- Ballade des gros dindons. / CHABRIER, ALEXIS EMMANUEL (1841-1894), MLM 178
  Paroles de Edmond Rostand. Musique de Emmanuel Chabrier. Paris, Enoch Frères & Costallat [1889] P1. no. E. F. & C.1699. First edition. Inscribed to Rostand by the composer. Piano and vocal score.
- Briséis. / CHABRIER, ALEXIS EMMANUEL (1841-1894), MLM 179
  Drame en trois actes. Musique de Emmanuel Chabrier. Partition piano et chant réduite par l'auteur. Paris, Enoch, c1897. P1. no. E. & C. 2006. First edition. The text is by Ephraim Mikhael and Catulle Mendès. The first act of Briséis was performed for the first time January 31, 1897, at the Concerts Lamoureux in Paris. Wotquenne, 2663.
- Autograph signed. / CHABRIER, ALEXIS EMMANUEL (1841-1894), MLM 179A
- [An autograph letter] / CHABRIER, ALEXIS EMMANUEL (1841-1894), MLM 179B
  An autograph letter to Vincent d'Indy, Paris, February 20, 1890 and ""Notes pour d'Indy"" in Chabrier's handwriting and signed with his initials, Paris, April, 1886.
- España. / CHABRIER, ALEXIS EMMANUEL (1841-1894), MLM 180
  Rapsodie pour orchestre. Partition d'orchestre... Emmanuel Chabrier. Paris, Enoch Frères & Costallat [1883] P1. no. E. F. & C. 891. First edition. Inscribed to Charles Lecocq by the composer.
- Gwendoline. / CHABRIER, ALEXIS EMMANUEL (1841-1894), MLM 181
  Opéra en 2 actes et 3 tableaux. Poème de Catulle Mendès. Musique de Emmanuel Chabrier. Partition piano et chant réduite par l'auteur... Paris, Enoch Frères & Costallat, 1886. P1. no. E. F. & C. 1212. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Kireevski by the composer. Presented for the first time at Brussels, April 10, 1886. Inserted is the original manuscript of a part of the overture (cf. separate entry).
- Gwendoline. / CHABRIER, ALEXIS EMMANUEL (1841-1894), MLM 182
  Original manuscript signed. ca. 1885. 1 leaf (2 pages) 27 x 25 cm. This consists of the first fifty bars of the overture. Inserted in the first edition of the piano and vocal score.
- Le roi malgré lui. / CHABRIER, ALEXIS EMMANUEL (1841-1894), MLM 183
  Opéra comique en 3 actes. Paroles de Emile de Najac & Paul Burani. Musique de Emmanuel Chabrier. Réduite par M. Auguste Bazille... Paris, Enoch Frères & Costallat, 1887. P1. no. E. F. & C. 1348. First edition. Inscribed to M. Léonce Détroyat by the composer. Presented for the first time at Paris, May 8, 1887. Wotquenne, 2662.
- L'anneau d'argent. Rondel. / CHAMINADE, CECILE (1857-1944), MLM 184
  Poésie de Rosemonde Gérard. Musique de C. Chaminade... No. 3, Basse ou contralto... Paris, Enoch Frères & Costallat [ca.1890] P1. no. E. F. & C. 1875. First edition. Inscribed by the composer.
- Les heureuses. / CHAMINADE, CECILE (1857-1944), MLM 185
  Poésie de Charles Fuster...en sol maj. (ton original)...C. Chaminade. Paris, Enoch, c1909. P1. no. E. & C. 6981. First edition. Inscribed to Suzanne Astruc by the composer.
- Scherzando pour piano par C. Chaminade. / CHAMINADE, CECILE (1857-1944), MLM 186
  Op. 10... Paris, Durand, Schoenewerk [ca. 1900] P1. no. D. S. & Cie. 2819. First edition. Inscribed to Mme. Albert Schiller by the composer.
- Didon. / CHARPENTIER, GUSTAVE (1860-), MLM 187
  Scène dramatique. Poème de M. Auge de Lassus. Musique de Gustave Charpentier... Paris, G. Hartmann [ca. 1887] P1. no. G. H. et Cie. 1806. First edition. Inscribed to Emma Calvé by the composer. Piano and vocal score.
- Impressions d'Italie. / CHARPENTIER, GUSTAVE (1860-), MLM 188
  Suite pour orchestre par Gustave Charpentier. 1. Sérénade; 2. A la fontaine; 3. A mules; 4. Sur les crines; 5. Napoli... Réduction à 4 mains par André Messager... Paris, H. Tellier, 1890. P1. no. 1093 (1-5) First edition. Inscribed to Edouard Colonne by the composer.
- Louise. / CHARPENTIER, GUSTAVE (1860-), MLM 189
  Roman musical en quatre actes et cinq tableaux de Gustave Charpentier. Partition piano et chant... Paris, Heugel, c1900. Pl. no. H. et Cie. 19659. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Argens by the composer. The inscription includes a bar of music from the score. Mlle. Argens sang the role of La Plieuse in the first production of the opera at the Théâtre National de l'Opéra-Comique, February 2, 1900.
- La vie du poète. / CHARPENTIER, GUSTAVE (1860-), MLM 190
  Symphonie-drame en trois actes et quatre tableux. Poème et musique de Gustave Charpentier. Partition chant et piano... Paris, Choudens Fils, c1892. P1. no. A. C. 8922. First edition. Inscribed to André Gresse by the composer.
- Cantique à l'épouse. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 191
  Original manuscript signed. June 23, 1898. 2 leaves (4 pages) 27 x 361/2 cm. Piano and vocal score. The song is by Albert Jounet.
- Chanson perpetuelle pour voix de soprano et orchestre. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 192
  Opus 37. Original manuscript. 1898. 6 leaves (7 pages) 27 x 351/2 cm. Piano and vocal score. The song is by Charles Cros.
- Chansons de Miarka. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 193
  Paroles de Jean Richepin. Les morts... Ernest Chausson. Op. 17. Paris, Bruneau [1888} P1. no. B. & Cie. 109. Inscribed to Mlle. Thérèse Roger by the composer. Piano and vocal score.
- Le colibri. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 194
  Mélodie pour une voix avec accompagnement de piano par Ernest Chausson... Paris, J. Hamelle [ca. 1882] P1. no. J. 1861 H. First edition. Inscribed to Mme. Pauline Roger by the composer. The words are by Leconte de Lisle.
- Concert en ré majeur pour piano, violon et quatuor à cordes. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 195
  I. Décidé, II. Sicilienne, III. Grave, IV. Finale. Op. 21... Paris, Librairie de l'art indépendant, 1894. P1. no. A. 1-2. At head of title: Ernest Chausson. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Thérèse Roger by the composer. With the separate parts for solo violin, first violin, second violin, violoncello, and alto. Wotquenne, 6468.
- Quelques danses pour piano...par Ernest Chausson. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 196
  (Op. 26) ...[Paris, E. Baudoux, 1896] P1. no. E. B. et Cie. 296. First edition. Inscribed to Sigismond S. Stojowsky by the composer. Contents: Dédicace, Sarabande; Pavane; Forlane.
- Cinq fantaisies pour piano par Ernest Chausson. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 197
  Op. 1... Paris, Durand, Schoenewerk [1878] P1. no. D. S. et Cie. 2624. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Adolphi by the composer. [Acid free copy available to use for photocopying.]
- Hébe. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 198
  Chanson grecque dans le mode phrygien pour une voix avec accompagnement de piano par Ernest Chausson... Paris, J. Hamelle [1882] Pl. no. J. 1862 H. Inscribed to Mme. Pauline Roger by the composer. The words are by L. Ackermann.
- La légende de Sainte Cécile. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 199
  Drame en trois actes en vers de Maurice Bouchor. Musique de Ernest Chausson. Op. 22. Représenté pour Ia premiere fois le 25 janvier 1892 à Paris sur le Petit Théâtre. Partition chant et piano. Paris, Ph. Maquet [ca 1892] P1. no. Ph. M. & Cie. 13,370. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Roger by the composer.
- 5 melodies pour mezzo-soprano ou baryton avec accompagnement de piano par Ernest Chausson. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 200
  .. Paris, J. Hamelle [1882] P1. no. J. 1960 H. First edition. Inscribed to Emmanuel Chabrier by the composer. Contents: ""Nanny"" (Leconte de Lisle), ""Le charme"" (Armand Silvestre), ""Les papillons"" (Théophile Gautier), ""La dernière feuille"" (Théophile Gautier), ""Sérénade italienne"" (Paul Bourget).
- La nuit. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 201
  Rondel a deux voix avec accompagnement de piano. Poésie de Tb. de Banville. Musique de Ernest Chausson... Paris, J. Hamelle [ca i88z] P1. no. J. 2767 H. Inscribed to Mme. Pauline Roger by the composer.
- Poème de l'amour-et de la mer (Maurice Bouchor). / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 202
  Pour une voix (élevée) et orchestre. Musique de Ernest Chausson. Op. 19. La fleur des eaux. Interlude. II. La mort de l'amour. Réduction de piano et chant... [Paris, E. Baudoux, ca. 1892] P1. nos. E. B. et Cie. 271-2. First edition. Inscribed to Mlle. Thérèse Roger by the composer.
- [Poème de l'amour et de lamer, opus 19" / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 203
  [A] Poème de l'amour et de la mer. II. La mort de l'amour [caption-title] Original manuscript signed. ca. 1882. 3 leaves (5 pages) 27 x 351/2 cm. Signature of Marie Escudier, one of the founders of La France musicale. [B] Poéme de l'amour et de la mer. Le temps des lilas. Original manuscript signed. ca. 1882. 4 leaves (title-page, 5 pages) 27 x 351/2 cm. Both manuscripts are the final movements in the printed score of Poème de l'amour et de la mer. II. La mort de l'amour. Manuscript [A] has three additional bars at the end. These do not appear in the first printed edition of the score. The text is by Maurice Bouchor.
- Symphonie en si bémol majeur [par] Ernest Chausson. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 204
  Op. 20. Partition d'orchestre... [Paris] E. Baudoux [1891] P1. no. E. B. et Cie. 338. First edition. Inscribed to Daniel De Lange by the composer.
- Viviane. / CHAUSSON, ERNEST (1855-1899), MLM 205
  Poème symphonique pour orchestre de Ernest Chausson. Op. 5. Partition d'orchestre... Paris, Le Bailly-O. Bornemann, successr. [1883] Pl. no. O. B. 4057. First edition. Inscribed to Daniel De Lange by the composer.
- Sinfonia de antigona / CHAVEZ, CARLOS (1899 - ), MLM 206
  New York, G. Schirmer [1948] P1. 42028. At head of title: Carlos Chavez. First edition. Inscribed by the composer. Orchestral score. Carlos Chavez has been the conductor of the Mexican Symphony Orchestra since 1928. The composer has used a background of Mexican folk music which under his sound artistry achieves distinction. The Sinfonia de antigona is one of his major works.
- Portrait (photograph) of the composer. / CHAVEZ, CARLOS (1899 - ), MLM 206A
- Sinfonia de antigona. / CHAVEZ, CARLOS (1899 - ), MLM 207
  Original manuscript, signed. 1933. 15 leaves (30 pages) 311/2 x 41 cm.
- Médée. / CHERUBINI, MARIA LUIGI CARLO ZENOBIO SALVATORE (1760-1842), MLM 208
  Opéra en 3 actes d'Hofman. [sic] Musique de Cherubini. Représenté [sic] dans le Théâtre de la Rue Feydeau... 13 mars 1797 Orchestral score. The complete holograph manuscript. 266 leaves (title-page as above, 528 pages) 22 x 29 cm. This manuscript is cle
- Médée. / CHERUBINI, MARIA LUIGI CARLO ZENOBIO SALVATORE (1760-1842), MLM 208A
  Opera in III actes, paroles d'Hoffmann musique de Cherubini...Paris, [1797] 388 leaves. Full score.
- Couplets pour la fête du Roi. / CHERUBINI, MARIA LUIGI CARLO ZENOBIO SALVATORE (1760-1842), MLM 209
  Original manuscript signed. 2 leaves(3 pages) 181/2 x 24 cm. Text without music. In Cherubini's Messe a trois voix.]
- Incarnatus, Crucifixus." / CHERUBINI, MARIA LUIGI CARLO ZENOBIO SALVATORE (1760-1842), MLM 209A
- Lodoïska. / CHERUBINI, MARIA LUIGI CARLO ZENOBIO SALVATORE (1760-1842), MLM 210